Okay, so I kind of just glossed over the
fact that you can put arrays inside of
objects. So this the goal of this video
is to go over that a little more slowly
and a little more detail. So um I've
created two objects here, my object and
my array. My object has one key or one
thing that I can look up called key and
it's storing an array.
So let's just So how would I access
number three?
Well,
let's go over how we'd access something
in an array. If we want to access
something in an array, we say the name
of the array and then we put square
braces. And then if I want to access the
three in this array, it's in the 0 1 2
position. So that's how I'd access
something in that array.
Okay, how do we access something in an
object? Well, there's two ways to do it.
We can say
my object at the key position
or we can say my object.key.
Those are both valid ways to access
something out of a dictionary.
So what is inside of my object key?
Well, my object key is storing an array.
So that means that this is an array. How
do we access something out of an array?
I showed you that on line 17. So what
that means is we can say go into my
object. How do you access something out
of an object? by using the dot notation
or the square braces. So I'll say my
object key and then here I'll say at the
two position. What that does is says go
into my object. Once you're there, look
for a key called key. Once you're there,
look for the look in the second index.
So 0 1 2 and that will access this
three. If I wanted to do it using this
syntax, I'd say my object at the key
position and then once I'm there, what's
there? An array. How do I access
something out of an array? I use square
braces and then I would say at the two
position. Both of these are valid ways
of accessing that number. And hopefully
that makes sense because all we're doing
is we're accessing something in an
object which happens to be an array. And
so how do you access something out of an
array? Well, with the syntax we just
showed you on line 17. And that's how
you access an array that's inside of an
object.